Garrett Albright • Drupal/PHP Web Developer

EMAIL contact@albright.pro · WEB albright.pro · DRUPAL www.drupal.org/u/garrett-albright

Profile

I've been a professional full-stack web developer since 2007 (and a hobbyist for many years before that). I specialize in back-end development with PHP, particularly with the Drupal content management system. I have contributed patches and projects back to the Drupal community; in particular, I developed the Pathologic module which is currently in use on about 68,000 Drupal sites. I also have done front-end development with JavaScript/jQuery, as well as Drupal theme development, including building themes from Photoshop mock-ups. I have a wide range of experience with sites and teams of various sizes and capabilities.

Other familiar technologies include the Git version control system, web server administration (with both Nginx and Apache on Linux and BSD), Cocoa and web development with Objective-C and Swift, and some Python and Java projects. I have presented at BADCamp 2013 and Boise Code Camp 2014. I speak native English and conversational Japanese.

Experience

FREELANCE - JANUARY 2013 - PRESENT

Various clients, both Japan- and America-based. Major projects include implementing PDF and ePub export and interactive maps at Gamer Guides (https://www.gamerguides.com), a video game strategy guide provider, and maintaining payment processor integration and various other tasks for GeekSuit (https://geeksuit.com), an operator of various technology- and mediarelated sites; client work included CentOS- and Ubuntu-based server system administration as well as back-end and front-end web development.

MILES MEDIA GROUP, SUPERIOR, CO, USA (TELECOMMUTE), SEP 2015 - FEB 2016
Front-end and back-end development for various tourism web sites, including those for Williamsburg, Virginia (https://www.visitwilliamsburg.com/), Mammoth Lakes, California (https://www.visitmammoth.com/), and the Washington DC area (https://www.capitalregionusa.org/).

FFW (FORMERLY PROPEOPLE), BOISE, ID, USA, AUG 2013 - AUGUST 2015

Major projects include various functionality for Box (https://box.com/); Formula X nail products brand (https://formulax.com/), for which I wrote most of the photo uploading and color/product matching and management functionality; revamping the California Certified Organic Farming site (https://ccof.org/); and internal sites for Stanford University.

PINGV, INC, BOULDER, CO, USA (TELECOMMUTE), AUG 2012 - JANUARY 2013
Assisted in the development of a Drupal 7-based site for our client, Dwell Magazine. Major projects included implementing "most read stories" lists and integration with the DoubleClick advertising system and Lyris mailing list management system, all via custom modules.

ALETHIA, TOKYO, JAPAN, JUNE 2011 - JULY 2012

Maintained several pre-built Drupal 6 and 7 sites, including e-commerce sites. Implemented a module to integrate e-commerce sites with the Japan-based GMO Payment Gateway payment processing system against documentation entirely in Japanese. Also spearheaded development of a large Drupal 7-powered corporate HR site with a wide range of capabilities, including browser-based layout modification.

GOINGON NETWORKS, SAN FRANCISCO, CA, USA (TELECOMMUTE), JULY 2010 - JUNE 2011 Worked with a small but talented development team in developing a Drupal 6-based platform for higher education, allowing students of classes to communicate online about course material. Made great use of Features for managing configuration in code.

Garrett Albright • Drupal/PHP Web Developer

EMAIL contact@albright.pro · WEB albright.pro · DRUPAL www.drupal.org/u/garrett-albright

PRECISION INTERMEDIA, FORTUNA, CA, USA, MAY 2007 - JUNE 2010

Developed several mostly small-scale Drupal sites, mostly for local clients. Oversaw transition from flat HTML or custom-built PHP sites to Drupal-based solutions for most of our web clients. Developed themes from Photoshop mock-ups by in-house artists. Maintained FreeBSD-based VPS for hosting.

Open source projects (partial list; contact for more)

PATHOLOGIC, DRUPAL MODULE, HTTPS://WWW.DRUPAL.ORG/PROJECT/PATHOLOGIC

Widely-used module which provides an input filter to correct image and link paths in content in situations which often causes them to "break," such as RSS syndication or moving content from a staging to a production environment. Originally published in 2008 and maintained ever since.

WPTRANS, IOS APPLICATION, HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/GARRETTALBRIGHT/WPTRANS

iOS application which uses the Wikipedia online encyclopedia as a multi-lingual dictionary. Complements traditional cross-language dictionaries, in that it works better for proper names and neologisms than standard dictionaries. Written in Objective-C. (Removed from the App Store after the Wikimedia Foundation claimed the app misused its copyrighted logo, despite the fact that it did not use its logo at all.)

Education

BS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT, 2015 - (ONGOING)

Western Governors University, Salt Lake City, UT (Online)

BA IN ENGLISH LITERATURE, 2000 - 2004

Sonoma State University, Rohnert Park, CA

Certifications

COMPTIA PROJECT+, APRIL 2019

Project management

CIW USER INTERFACE DESIGNER, JANUARY 2019

General user interface design consideration

CIW ADVANCED HTML5 AND CSS3, DECEMBER 2018

General client-side web development

COMPTIA A+, JULY 2015

General computer system maintenance skills

COMPTIA NETWORK+, DECEMBER 2015

Computer networking implementation and maintenance skills

ACQUIA CERTIFIED DEVELOPER, APRIL 2014

Drupal back-end and front-end development and administration expertise